<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lamprey Labs</title>
    <link>https://lampreylabs.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lamprey Labs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under the GNU General Public License v3.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lampreylabs.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Practical Reverse Engineering - Exercise 1, Page 11</title>
      <link>https://lampreylabs.com/posts/2022/07/practical-reverse-engineering-exercise-1-page-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lampreylabs.com/posts/2022/07/practical-reverse-engineering-exercise-1-page-11/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Question Answer  Question This function uses a combination SCAS and STOS to do its work. First, explain what is the type of the [EBP+8] and [EBP+C] in line 1 and 8, respectively. Next, explain what this snippet does.
01: mov edi, [ebp + 8] 02: mov edx, edi 03: xor eax, eax 04: or ecx, 0FFFFFFFFh 05: repne scasb 06: add ecx, 2 07: neg ecx 08: mov al, [ebp + 0Ch] 09: mov edi, edx 10: rep stosb 11: mov eax, edx Answer [EBP + 8h] appears to be a char buffer pointer/PCHAR(size = 4 bytes) since it is loaded into EDI register which is then implicitly used by scasb instruction with repne prefix as the memory operand address to compare for a particular byte value specified by AL register.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://lampreylabs.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lampreylabs.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey there! My name&amp;rsquo;s Upayan. I predominantly go by my &amp;ldquo;winterknife&amp;rdquo; alias nowadays.
I am a software engineer; my interests revolve around the following topics:
 Arcane knowledge of Windows system internals x86 ISA User-mode and kernel-mode CNO Software Development Vulnerability Research and Exploitation  I use the skills gained from my relentless pursuit of the above to solve hard problems in support of the information security industry.
This blog is where I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing random thoughts, experiments and projects pertaining to low-level computer systems research and software development.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
